Guide to the Frank Pagliaro Construction Records Collection 1914-1971 PR 282
New-York Historical Society
Frank Pagliaro Construction Records Collection
1914-1971
New-York Historical Society
PR 282
9 Linear feet
The Frank Pagliaro Construction Records Collection contains materials from 1914-1971 (bulk 1960-69) relating to the Pagliaro family concrete contractor and sub-contractor businesses. Materials include, but are not limited to progress photos, financial documents, correspondence, blueprints, artist renderings of sites, and promotional materials.
Provenance
Gift of the Selz and Pagliaro families, 2010.
Access
Materials in this collection may be stored offsite. For more information on making arrangements to consult them, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.
Portions of the collection that have been photocopied or microfilmed will be brought to the researcher in that format; microfilm can be made available through Interlibrary Loan.
Permission to Reproduce
Application to use images from this collection for publication should be made in writing to the Department of Rights and Reproductions, The New-York Historical Society, 170 Central Park West, New York, NY 10024. Permission to reproduce or quote text from this collection in a publication must be requested from and granted in writing by the Library Director, The New-York Historical Society, 170 Central Park West, New York, NY 10024.
Biographical Note
Ignazio Pagliaro (c. 1876-1938) immigrated to the United States from Italy at the age of 14 and ran the concrete sub-contractor business known as Knickerbocker Inc. in partnership with its founder Luigi Gerbino (d. 1930s). Ignazio continued to run the business as a joint venture after Luigi's death, sometimes assuming the name of the deceased.
Ignazio's son, Frank Pagliaro Sr. (1900-1999), studied civil engineering at Cornell University in the early 1920s and inherited the family concrete sub-contracting business from his father after graduation. During Frank Sr.'s tenure the company grew from sub-contracting to general contracting. Knickerbocker Inc., functioned as the parent company of many incorporated businesses such as Knickerbocker Construction Co.; Knickerbocker Fireproofing & Concrete Co., Inc.; IP Co. (Ignazio Pagliari Co.); Contel Construction Co.; and various incorporated businesses named after the address of a management/construction site (e.g. Fifth Avenue & 46th Street Corp.). Knickerbocker Inc. is believed to be the largest family-owned North American concrete construction company of its time.
Knickerbocker Inc. was dissolved in the 1970s. The Pagliaro family has cited pressure from the Italian Mafia--widely known to control aspects of concrete/construction contracts at the time--as the primary reason for the company's demise.
Scope and Contents
The Frank Pagliaro Construction Records Collection contains materials from 1914-1971 (bulk 1960-69) relating to the Pagliaro family concrete contractor and sub-contractor business.
Materials include progress photos, financial documents, correspondence, blueprints, artist renderings of sites, and promotional materials.
Records in the collection relate to projects in the United States with a focus on New York City sites. Highlights include the Chrysler Building, the United Nations Building, Shea Stadium, and the Huntington Hartford Gallery on Columbus Circle in New York City, and the Court House & Federal Office Building in San Francisco. While this collection contains extensive records on certain projects and companies, it does not represent a complete set of records for either. Most extensive are the progress photographs on the Court House & Federal Office Building in San Francisco and year-end expense ledgers detailing the annual cash expenditures of Knickerbocker Inc. from 1953-1957.
The collection also includes some personal effects of Frank Pagliaro and Ignazio Pagliaro. Noteworthy is a series of Frank's graded Cornell University College of Civil Engineering Exams dating from 1921-1924.
Arrangement Note
The collection is ordered into 13 series.
The first 7 series are records related to specific construction sites and are arranged alphabetically by state, city, and project. The remaining series consist of general business records, architectural publications, and miscellaneous personal papers.
Breaks in box number continuity occur when oversized materials did not fit into the general organization (i.e. bound, matted, oversized materials).
Missing Title
Missing Title
Series I: California Construction Sites
Series II: Massachusetts Construction Sites
Series III: New York Construction Sites
Series IV: Pennsylvania Construction Sites
Series V: Virginia Construction Sites
Series VI: Washington D.C. Sites
Series VII: Unidentified Sites
Series VIII: Construction Corporations
Series IX: Miscellaneous
Series X: Frank Pagliaro Personal Effects
Series XI: Louis (Luigi) Gerbino Personal Effects
Series XII: Cornell University Exam Books
Series XIII: Architect Publications
Sources
The concrete industry board of New York city...its Purposes, Methods and Accomplishments (1959). Retrieved January 28, 2011, from ftp://66.151.101.167/woc/C590715.PDF
Gerbino, Luigi/Ignazio Pagliaro Obituary, New York City, Herald Tribune, June 7th, 1938, p. 14.
Pagliaro, Ignazio Obituary, New York City, New York Times, June 7th, 1938. Retrieved January 28, 2011 from http://select.nytimes.com/gst/abstract.html?res=F10913F73F55157A93C5A9178DD85F4C8385F9
Pagliaro, Frank Obituary, New York City, New York Times, June 24, 1999. Retrieved January 28, 2011 from http://www.nytimes.com/1999/06/24/nyregion/frank-pagliaro-99-concrete-contractor.html?scp=1&sq=frank%20pagliaro&st=cse
Magnuson, Ed, Hitting the Mafia. [Electronic version]. (2001). Time.com. Retrieved January 28, 2011 from http://www.time.com/time/magazine/article/0,9171,1101860929-145082,00.html
Realty Notes, New York Times, November 4, 1921. Retrieved January 28, 2011 from http://select.nytimes.com/gst/abstract.html?res=F10913F73F55157A93C5A9178DD85F4C8385F9&scp=1&sq=ignazio%20pagliaro&st=cse
Real Estate Record and Builders' Guide, v. 93, no 2415: Articles: June 27, 1914. New York: F.W. Dodge Corp., p. 1032.
Rowan, Roy, The Mafia's Bite of the Big Apple: Byzantine Building Codes and Horrendous Logistics Help the Mob Control New York City Construction –at a Price That the Big Developers Have Been All Too Willing to Pay. [Electronic version]. (1988). CNNMoney.com. Retrieved January 28, 2011 from http://money.cnn.com/magazines/fortune/fortune_archive/1988/06/06/70628/index.htm
Manning, Vice Admiral John J., The Concrete Industry Board of New York City…Its Purposes, Methods and Accomplishments, Publication #C590715, 1959. Retrieved January 28, 2011 from ftp://66.151.101.167/woc/C590715.PDF
Wages; Stock certificates.; New York (N.Y.) -- Buildings, structures, etc.; New York (N.Y.); Memorandums.; Leases.; Invoices.; Checks (bank checks); Account books.; Accounts.; Annual reports.; California; Color slides.; Columbus Circle (New York, N.Y.); Concrete; Contracts.; Financial records.; Hotels.; Massachusetts; Pennsylvania; Civil engineering -- Examinations, questions, etc.; Luna Park (New York, N.Y.); Financial statements.; Chrysler Building (New York, N.Y.); Cornell University; Rockefeller Center
- Series I: California Construction Sites, 1961-1968
  - Subseries I: Berkeley
    - Satellite Senior Homes, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - University of California, Berkeley: Progress Photos & Correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - University of California, Berkeley: Progress Photos & Correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Subseries II: San Francisco
    - Court House & Federal Office Building: Ground-breaking Ceremony Photos & Correspondence, c. 1961 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Court House & Federal Office Building: Progress Photos, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Court House & Federal Office Building: Progress Photos, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Court House & Federal Office Building: Progress Photos, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Court House & Federal Office Building: Progress Photos, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Court House & Federal Office Building: Progress Photos & Correspondence, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Court House & Federal Office Building: Progress Photos, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Court House & Federal Office Building: Progress Photos, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Court House & Federal Office Building: Progress Photos & Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Court House & Federal Office Building: Progress Photos, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Court House & Federal Office Building: Progress Photos, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Court House & Federal Office Building: Progress Photos, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Court House & Federal Office Building: Progress Photos, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Court House & Federal Office Building: Progress Photos - Oversized, c. 1961 (Box 16, Folder 129)
    - Jackson Towers: Progress Photos & Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Jackson Towers: Related News Clippings & Small Progress Photos, 1955 - 1965 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Jackson Towers: Completed Project Photo - Oversized, 1955-1956 (Box 16, Folder 130)
    - Jackson Towers: Completed Project Photo - Oversized (Box 20, Folder 147)
  - Subseries III: Sausalito
    - 565 Bellevue Apartments: Progress Photos & Correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Industrial Center Building: Progress Photos, c. 1963 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Westlake Christian Terrace: Progress Photos & Correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Subseries IV: Sherman Oaks (?)
    - Westminster Towers: Photos, Rendering, & Correspondence, c. 1969 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Series II: Massachusetts Construction Sites (Boston) (Unknown container 251 for instance of Series II: Massachusetts Construction Sites (Boston))
  - Bay Towers Project: Progress Photos, c. 1971 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Bay Towers: Rolled Architectural Drawings - Oversized, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Bay Towers: Rolled Architectural Drawings - Oversized, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Series III: New York Construction Sites
  - Subseries I: Mount Vernon
    - Gramanton Apartments: Correspondence, Property Survey, 1922-1923 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Gramanton Apartments: Fireproofing & Other Improvement Documents, Promotional Materials, & Correspondence, c. 1923 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Subseries II: New Rochelle
    - Main St. New Rochelle, Unknown (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Subseries III: New York City, Bronx
    - Bronx River Houses: Mounted Rendering - Oversized, Unknown (Box 19, Folder 143)
    - Kips Bay, Bronx Park East, Dick Job, Roachdale Ryan Plant Magazine of 35mm Slides (Box 17)
    - Skyview on the Hudson, Arlington Ave. & 257th St.: Progress Photos - Oversized, c. 1962 (Box 16, Folder 131)
  - Subseries IV: New York City, Brooklyn
    - Fort Greene Houses: Progress Photos & Promo Rendering, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Franklin K. Lane High School, 999 Jamaica Ave.: Completed Building Photograph, Unknown (Box Flat File, Folder OS 1)
    - Franklin K. Lane High School, 999 Jamaica Ave.: Progress Photos, c. 1936 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Luna Park: Blueprints, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Luna Park: Blueprints, c. 1959 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Luna Park: Blueprints, 1959-1960 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Luna Park: Drawing Related Documents - Schedules, Correspondence & Transmittals, 1958-1960 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Luna Park: Financial Records - Bethlehem Steel Orders, Transmittals, & Related, 1958-1959 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Luna Park: Financial Records - Bethlehem Steel, Transmitalls, & Related Documents, c. 1959 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Luna Park: Financial Records - Bethlehem Steel Orders & Related, c. 1960 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Luna Park: Financial Records & Receipts (General), 1959-1960 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Luna Park: Ledger (Unknown Document), c. 1958 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Luna Park: Misc. Bulletins, Transmittals, & Correspondence, c. 1959-1961 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Luna Park: Misc. Correspondence & Changes to Plans, 1958-1960 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Luna Park: Misc. Vent Openings & Plumbing Details & Materials Lists, Unknown (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Neptune Ave. & West 5th Street: Progress Photos - Oversized, 1963 (Box 16, Folder 132)
    - Nostrand Houses: Mounted Rendering - Oversized, Unknown (Box 19, Folder 143)
    - Sheepshead Bay Houses: Mounted Rendering, Unknown (Box 19, Folder 143)
    - Warbasse Houses: Magazine of 35mm Slides (Box 17)
  - Subseries V: New York City, Manhattan
    - 232 W. 26th St.: Expense Report, 1927 (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - 56 W. 45th St.: Mechanics Lien Filed by Knickerbocker Fireproofing Co. Inc. & Contract, 1931 (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - 2-8 West 46th St.: Fifth Avenue & 46th Street Corp., Lease Ledgers & Maintenance Documents, 1923-1933 (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - 135 W. 50th St. - Magazine of 35mm Slides (Box 17)
    - 3 E. 54th St.: Promotional Rendering, Purchase Documents, Correspondence, & Insurance Documents, 1968-1969 (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - 109 E. 56th St.: Materials Contract, 1926 (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - 61st St. & Park Ave.: Progress & Promotional Photos, Unknown (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - 69th and 2nd Ave.: Progress Photos - Oversized, 1962 (Box 16, Folder 133)
    - 74th St. & 5th Ave.: Expense Report, Unknown (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - 26 W. 84th St.: Blue Print, Unknown (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - 113 E. 86th St.: Concrete Ledger & Payroll, 1927 (Box 6, Folder 49)
    - 241 W. 108th St.: Mortgage Documents, 1922 (Box 6, Folder 50)
    - 610 W. 110th St.: Lease Documents, Building Expenditures, Building Appraisal, 1923-1943 (Box 6, Folder 51)
    - 165 W. 160th St.: Statement of Income & Profit / 709 W. 169th St.: Mortgage Documents & Wage Books, 1923 (Box 6, Folder 52)
    - Abraham Lincoln Houses: Mounted Rendering - Oversized, Unknown (Box 19, Folder 143)
    - Alpha Garage, 13-17 E. 54th St.: Progress Photos, c. 1964 (Box 6, Folder 53)
    - Alpha Garage, 13-17 E. 54th St.: Progress Photos, c. 1964 (Box 20, Folder 147)
    - Chrysler Building: Carpenter & Concrete Laborer Cost Ledger, c. 1920 (Box 6, Folder 54)
    - Colonial Park Houses: Mounted Rendering - Oversized, Unknown (Box 19, Folder 143)
    - El Dorado, Central Park West & 90th-91st Sts.: Knickerbocker Fireproofing Work Order, 1930 (Box 6, Folder 55)
    - Gallery of Modern Art, Columbus Circle: Progress Photos - Oversized, Unknown (Box 16, Folder 134)
    - Guaranty Trust Co. Building, 44th St. & 5th Ave.: Progress Photos - Oversized, 1920 (Box 16, Folder 135)
    - James Weldon Johnson Houses: Mounted Photo, Unknown (Box 19, Folder 143)
    - Jeffrey House: Progress Photos - Oversize, 1961 (Box 16, Folder 136)
    - Lillian Wald Houses: Mounted Photos, Unknown (Box 19, Folder 143)
    - Lincoln Square - 3 Magazines of 35mm Slides (Box 17)
    - Lincoln Towers, West 70th & West End Ave: Progress Photos - Oversized, 1961-1963 (Box 16, Folder 137)
    - New York Athletic Club: Concrete Ledger & Payroll Roster, 1927 (Box 6, Folder 56)
    - New York Coliseum (Collapse) - Progress Photos, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 57)
    - 7 Penn Plaza, Mounted Photograph - Oversized (Box 20, Folder 147)
    - Radio City: Carpenters, Concrete Laborers, & Wire Latherers Payroll, 1920-1939 (Box 6, Folder 58)
    - 370 Riverside Dr.: Lease Documents, Building Maintenance & Expense Documents, Building Appraisal, 1925-1943 (Box 6, Folder 59)
    - 370 Riverside Dr. - Lease Ledgers & Legal Paperwork, 1928-1932 (Box 6, Folder 60)
    - Rockefeller Center: Photos of Completed Buildings & Knickerbocker Concrete Order, c. 1936 - (Box 6, Folder 61)
    - Roosevelt/Welfare Island: Aerial Photograph, Unknown (Box Flat File, Folder OS1)
    - The Satcher House, 81st St. & 12 Ave.: Progress Photos - Oversized, 1961 (Box 16, Folder 138)
    - 898 West End Ave.: Building Safety Correspondence, Lease Documents, Building Expenditures, etc., 1928-1937 (Box 6, Folder 62)
    - The Windmere, 666 West End Ave.: Cost Sheets, Lease Documents, Account Documents, etc., 1926-1928 (Box 7, Folder 63)
    - The Windmere, 666 West End Ave.: Lease Documents, Maintenance Correspondence, Floor Plan, etc., 1930-1939 (Box 7, Folder 64)
    - The Windmere, 666 West End Ave.: Maintenance Correspondence & Receipts, Accounts Ledger, etc., c. 1929 (Box 7, Folder 65)
  - Subseries VI: New York City, Queens
    - Carlyle Towers: Progress Photos - Oversized, 1961 (Box 16, Folder 139)
    - Flushing Stadium (Shea Stadium): 4 Magazines of 35mm Slides (Box 17)
    - Flushing Stadium (Shea Stadium): Progress Photos, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 66)
  - Subseries VII: Multiple New York City Buildings
    - Multiple Buildings/Projects Contracts & Specs, 1912-1929 (Box 7, Folder 67)
    - Multiple Buildings: Chrysler Building & Others - Cost Sheets, 1920-1939 (Box 7, Folder 68)
    - Multiple Buildings' Payroll Ledgers, 1936-1937 (Box 7, Folder 69)
    - Multiple Buildings, New York City Schools - Photos of Completed Structures & Misc. (Box 7, Folder 70)
  - Subseries VIII: New York State
    - Thruway Bridge (Thru Way Bridge): Magazine of 35mm Slides (Box 18)
- Series IV: Pennsylvania Construction Sites
  - Subseries I: Philadelphia
    - 56th & Lindburg, Philadelphia Housing Authority: Progress Photographs, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 71)
    - Bartrum Village Project: Progress Photographs - Negatives, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 72)
    - Defense Housing Project PA 36015: Panoramic Photographs, Unknown (Box Flat File, Folder OS2)
    - Four Freedoms: Progress & Promotional Photographs, Unknown (Box 8, Folder 73)
    - Philadelphia State Hospital: Progress Photographs & Correspondence, 1942-1943 (Box 8, Folder 74)
    - Philip Murray House: Progress & Promotional Photographs, c. 1967 (Box 8, Folder 75)
    - Poplar Street Project: Progress Photographs & Negatives, c. 1941 (Box 8, Folder 76)
    - Poplar Street Project: Panoramic Photographs, Unknown (Box Flat File, Folder OS 3)
    - Unidentified Philadelphia Site, Progress Photos, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 77)
  - Subseries II: Pittsburgh
    - "The Pittsburgh Job": Correspondence Regarding a Concrete Order, 1932 (Box 8, Folder 78)
    - Pittsburgh Memorial Hospital: Progress Photos, Unknown (Box 8, Folder 79)
    - U.S. Post Office & Court House: Progress Photos, 1932 (Box 8, Folder 80)
- Series V: Virginia Construction Sites
  - Naval Operating Base: Photo of Site & Correspondence Regarding Floor Repair, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 81)
- Series VI: Washington D.C. Sites
  - Statler Hotel: Progress Photos, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 82)
- Series VII: Unidentified Sites
  - Artist Renderings, Unknown (Box Flat File, Folder OS 4)
  - Beechcroft: Magazine of 35mm Slides (Box 18)
  - Downstate: Magazine of 35mm Slides (Box 18)
  - Electric Industry: 2 Magazines of 35mm Slides (Box 18)
  - Miscellaneous: Magazine of 35mm Slides (Box 18)
  - Miscellaneous: 5 Reels of 1 1/2 MIL MYLAR 1200 or 3600 FT, Illegible or Unlabeled (Box 18)
  - Panoramic Photographs, Unknown (Box Flat File, Folder OS 5)
  - Unidentified Building: Contract for Flooring, Carvert Holding Co. & Luigi Gerbino, 1912 (Box 9, Folder 83)
  - Unidentified Building: Progress Photos, Unknown (Box 9, Folder 84)
  - Unidentified Building: Progress Photos, Unknown (Box 9, Folder 85)
  - Unidentified Building: Progress Photos - Oversized, Unknown (Box 16, Folder 140)
  - Unidentified Building: Progress Photos - Small, 1942 (Box 9, Folder 86)
  - Unidentified Building: Promotional Rendering & Apartment Listing, Unknown (Box 9, Folder 87)
  - Unidentified Buildings: Rent Ledger, 1928-1930 (Box 9, Folder 88)
  - Unidentified Housing Project, Brown & Lescaze Assoc. Architects: Mounted Rendering, Unknown (Box 19, Folder 143)
- Series VIII: Construction Corporations
  - Contel Construction Corporation: Promotional Book, c. 1960s (Box 9, Folder 89)
  - IP Company, Inc.: Financial Holdings Listing (Ignazio Pagliaro), 1927 (Box 9, Folder 90)
  - Knickerbocker Construction Corporation & Frank Pagliaro Cash Lists, Cancelled Checks & Wage Books, 1930-1970 (Box 9, Folder 91)
  - Knickerbocker Fireproofing Company, Inc.: Accounts Payable, Balance Sheets (1927), Audit (1928), Injury Listing (1928-29) & Others, 1928-1929 (Box 9, Folder 92)
  - Knickerbocker/Roscoe Energy Cor./Ajax Const. Co. Inc. & Assoc.: Payroll Records (Possibly pertaining to CIA Building, Washington), 1958-1959 (Box 9, Folder 93)
  - Knickerbocker/Roscoe Energy Cor./Ajax Const. Co. Inc. & Assoc. (Possibly pertaining to CIA Building, Washington), 1959 (Box 9, Folder 94)
  - Knickerbocker/Roscoe Energy Cor./Ajax Const. Co. Inc. & Assoc.: Payroll Records (Possibly pertaining to CIA Building, Washington), 1959 (Box 10, Folder 95)
  - Knickerbocker/Roscoe Energy Cor./Ajax Const. Co. Inc. & Assoc.: Payroll Records (Possibly pertaining to CIA Building, Washington), 1959-1960 (Box 10, Folder 96)
  - Unidentified Company, Cash Disbursements, 1953 (Box 19, Folder 144)
  - Unidentified Company, Cash Disbursements (Box 19, Folder 145)
  - Unidentified Company, Cash Disbursements - Oversized, 1955 (Box 20, Folder 148)
  - Unidentified Company, Cash Disbursements - Oversized (Box 20, Folder 149)
  - Unidentified Company, Cash Disbursements - Oversized, 1957 (Box 20, Folder 150)
  - Unidentified Building.: Proposal & Financial Records, 1913-1922 (Box 10, Folder 97)
  - Unidentified Building: Fireproofing League of New York Proposal (1926), Bureau of Concrete Service, Inc. Member Form (1929), 1926, 1929 (Box 10, Folder 98)
  - Bound Stock Certificates: Anaco, Knickerbocker Concrete Arch., Knickerbocker Const. Co., 1938-1949 (Box 10, Folder 99)
  - Bound Stock Certificates: Knickerbocker Const. Co., Knickerbocker Fireproofing Const. Inc., 3 E. 45th St. Inc., 1938-1949 (Box 10, Folder 100)
- Series IX: Miscellaneous
  - The Fair Waist & Dress Co. Inc. vs. Harry A. Kaplan Law Suit, 1922 (Box 11, Folder 101)
  - Misc. Checkbooks & Bankbooks, Knickerbocker & Others, 1913-1929 (Box 11, Folder 102)
  - Personal Brochures, Promotional Materials, Schedules, Maps, etc., 1920-1970 (Box 11, Folder 103)
  - Unattributed Checkbooks, 1919-1929 (Box 11, Folder 104)
  - Wage Books, 1923 (Box 11, Folder 105)
  - Prints: Views of New York City by John Jackson, Nat Lowell, Vernon Howe Bailey, and Unknown (Box Flat File, Folder OS 6)
  - 35 mm Argus Color Slide Magazines - Progress Photos, 16 boxes - Flushing (Shea) Stadium, Lincoln Square, Electric Industry, Thruway Bridge, 135 W. 50th St., Warbasse Houses, Beechcroft, Downstate, Kips Bay, Bronx Park East, Dick Job, Roachdale Ryan Plant & Miscellaneous (Box 17, Box-folder unknown container)
  - 35 mm Argus Color Slide Magazines - Progress Photos, 16 boxes - Flushing (Shea) Stadium, Lincoln Square, Electric Industry, Thruway Bridge, 135 W. 50th St., Warbasse Houses, Beechcroft, Downstate, Kips Bay, Bronx Park East, Dick Job, Roachdale Ryan Plant & Miscellaneous (Box 18)
  - 1 1/2 Mil Mylar Reel to Reel film, Unknown Subject
  - Promotional Materials - Oversized (Box 20, Folder 146)
  - Photos and Renderings of Completed Buildings - Oversized (Box 20, Folder 147)
- Series X: Frank Pagliaro Personal Effects
  - Pagliaro, Frank: Personal Effects - Correspondence & Small Notebook, 1920s (Box 12, Folder 106)
  - Pagliaro, Frank: Personal Effect, Cornell University, 1920-1940 (Box 12, Folder 107)
  - Pagliaro, Frank: Personal Finances (c. 1919 - 1925) (Box 12, Folder 108)
  - Pagliaro, Frank: Personal Finances (c. 1925 - 1930) (Box 12, Folder 109)
  - Pagliaro, Frank: Personal Finances, Checks on The First National Bank, Ithaca, NY, 1921-1923 (Box 12, Folder 110)
- Series XI: Louis (Luigi) Gerbino Personal Effects
  - Louis Gerbino Italian Organizations: Casa Italiana, Fascisti League, & Mostra di Newark (Book Sales), 1928-1935 (Box 13, Folder 111)
  - Louis Gerbino Stock Market Analysis Prepared by Dean C. Molleson, 1929 (Box 13, Folder 112)